# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道主食
In this video I'm sharing an iconic dish with you.
# 扬州炒饭
Yangzhou Fried Rice
# 黄金蛋丝
Golden shredded eggs, every grain of rice is perfectly separated.
# 鲜虾
Fresh shrimp
# 宣威火腿
Xuanwei ham
# 水发海参
Rehydrated sea cucumber
# 首先我们准备普通米饭400克
First let's prepare 400 grams of cooked rice.
# 然后加入适量的猪油搅拌均匀备用
Then stir in some lard.
# 加猪油的目的是增加米饭的香味
The purpose of adding lard is to add aroma to the rice.
# 也可以使其下锅后受热温度快速提升
It can also raise the cooking temperature quickly during stir-frying.
# 当然不喜欢的同学也可以不加
Of course, if you don't like it, you can skip it.
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Start preparing the other ingredients next.
# 准备水发海参1只竖着切开之后切碎备用
Prepare 1 rehydrated sea cucumber, cut it vertically and chop it into fine pieces.
# 干海参泡发需要很长一段时间且过程复杂
Dried sea cucumbers take a long time to rehydrate and the process is complicated.
# 嫌麻烦的同学可以直接购买速食海参
For those of you who don't like the hassle, you can buy instant sea cucumber directly.
# 准备煮熟的宣威火腿1小块
Prepare 1 small piece of cooked Xuanwei ham
# 切成均匀的小颗粒备用
Cut into small, uniform pieces.
# 同学们切记最好用比较瘦的火腿
Remember, it's best to use the leaner part of the ham.
# 这样才能够减少油腻
This will reduce the greasy feeling.
# 发挥其最大的香味
Also to bring out its maximum fragrance.
# 准备适量带皮熟鸡腿肉切成小颗粒备用
Prepare a portion of skin-on cooked chicken thigh, cut into small pieces.
# 同学们也可以选择熟鸡脯肉代替鸡腿
You can also use cooked chicken breast instead of chicken thigh.
# 准备几颗煮熟的干贝撕成细丝备用
Prepare a few cooked dried scallops torn into thin strips.
# 最好选择直径8毫米以上的优质干贝
It is best to choose high quality scallops with a diameter of 8 mm or more.
# 撕成细丝是为了更好地释放其特有的鲜味
Torn into thin strips for better release of its characteristic umami taste.
# 准备煮熟漂过水的鲜笋1小块切成小颗粒备用
Prepare 1 small piece of cooked and blanched bamboo shoots, cut into small pieces.
# 鲜笋粒的加入会有明显的口感和鲜味
The addition of fresh bamboo shoot dice will provide a noticeable texture and
# 当然没有鲜笋的同学也可以选择水发笋
Of course, if you don't have access to fresh bamboo shoots, you can also choose rehydrated bamboo shoots.
# 准备水发花菇2朵切成小颗粒备用
Prepare 2 rehydrated shiitake mushrooms, cut into small pieces.
# 花菇最好提前用温水泡发
Shiitake mushrooms are best soaked in warm water in advance.
# 准备适量焯水断生的豌豆备用
Prepare some blanched half cooked peas.
# 最好选择碧绿鲜嫩的豌豆
It's best to choose green, tender peas.
# 准备几个鲜虾剥皮之后去除虾线然后切成颗粒备用
Prepare a few fresh shrimps, peel them, remove the sand veins and cut them into pieces.
# 同学们鲜活的虾不好去壳
It's hard to remove the shells from fresh shrimp.
# 我们可以先将其急冻2个小时
We can freeze them for two hours.
# 这样更方便剥壳
Make it easier to shell.
# 然后我们在虾仁中加入适量的淀粉抓匀备用
Then we added some starch to the shrimp and mix it well.
# 这一步的目的是防止焯水的时候水分流失导致肉质发柴
The purpose of this step is to prevent the loss of moisture during parboil, which can cause the meat to become chewy.
# 下一步我们开始准备蛋液
Next we'll start preparing the egg.
# 碗中打入全蛋2颗（鸡蛋）
Beat 2 whole eggs in a bowl.
# 然后加入纯蛋黄4个
Then add 4 egg yolks.
# 顺着搅拌均匀备用
Mix well in one direction.
# 搅拌均匀之后用密漏过滤中间白色的结块
Mix well and then strain the white clumps through a sieve.
# 最后准备适量的小葱切碎备用
Finally, prepare a generous amount of chopped scallions for later use.
# 下一步我们开始制作
Next let's start cooking.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First heat up the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入“小宽油”
When the wok is hot, add small Kuan You (literally "broad oil")
# 油温烧至90度之后开始缓缓地下入蛋液
Heat the oil to 90 °C and start to slowly add the egg mixture.
# 同学们切记蛋液必须形成1根细丝下锅
Remember that the egg mixture must form a thin thread into the wok.
# 否则下太快很容易变成“蛋花”而非“蛋丝”
If you don't, it's easy to become "egg flower" instead of "egg shreds".
# 待蛋丝成型之后即可倒出备用
When the egg shreds are formed, it's ready to be poured out
# 然后用炒勺从上至下挤出多余的油
Then squeeze out the excess oil with a frying spoon.
# 如果蛋丝不能很好地控制油脂
You need to control the oil of the egg shreds.
# 炒饭就会变得很油腻
Otherwise the fried rice will become greasy.
# 蛋丝控油之后锅中加入适量的清水
After finished with egg shreds, add some water to the wok.
# 大火烧开之后加入虾仁焯水断生备用
Add in the shrimp on high heat and blanch it to half cook.
# 然后重新把锅烧热加入少许的底油
Then reheat the pan and add some base oil.
# 油温5成热之后将准备好的辅料依次下入锅中
When the oil temperature is at 50% (150°C), add the other prepared ingredients to the wok.
# 其中包括宣威火腿
Including Xuanwei ham.
# 手撕干贝
Hand-shredded dried scallops.
# 花菇颗粒
Shiitake mushroom granules.
# 鸡腿肉颗粒
Chicken thigh meat granules.
# 海参颗粒
Sea cucumber granules.
# 鲜笋颗粒
Fresh bamboo shoot granules.
# 加入鲜虾仁之后翻炒几下爆出香味
And the shrimp, stir-fry everything a few times to release the aroma.
# 中途加入炸好的蛋丝炒散备用
Then add the egg shreds and stir up.
# 蛋丝炒散之后加入米饭和青豆翻炒均匀
After egg, add rice and green peas and stir-fry.
# 米饭翻炒均匀之后加入适量的葱花翻炒几下
After the rice has been tossed evenly, add some scallions and continue to stir-fry a few times.
# 然后再次加入葱花翻炒
Then add some more scallions again.
# 下一步开始调味
The next step is seasoning.
# 锅中加入适量的食用盐
Add in some salt.
# 加入少许生抽酱油从锅边淋入
Add a bit soy sauce from the side of wok.
# 然后继续翻炒均匀
Then continue to toss and fry everything evenly.
# 中途将鼓风机的风门关小减少通风量
Close the blower in the middle of the process to reduce stove airflow.
# 这一步的目的是散开火力增加明火使其均匀受热
The purpose of this step is to spread the fire and increase the open flame so that it heats the wok more evenly.
# 然后翻炒出锅气之后加入剩余的葱花翻炒均匀即可出锅装盘
Then stir-fry the rice until there is wok hei, then add the remaining scallions and stir-fry evenly to serve.
# 一道非常美味的扬州炒饭就制作完成
A very tasty Yangzhou fried rice is ready!
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一
First,
# 所有原料中包括火腿
Amount all the ingredients, include ham
# 海参
sea cucumbers
# 鲜笋
fresh bamboo shoots
# 干贝
dried scallops
# 花菇（等）都要事先经过焯水和煮制
Shiitake mushrooms (etc.) are blanched and cooked in advance.
# 第二
Second,
# 米饭煮熟之后最好待其自然凉透之后再翻炒
After the rice is cooked, it is best to let it cool naturally before stir-frying.
# 否则热饭中水分较多很容易炒成团状
Otherwise, the hot rice will be easily fried into a ball if there is too much water in it.
# 第三
Third,
# 蛋液下锅不能太快
Don't add the egg mixture too fast.
# 必须像1根线一样下锅
It must go down like a string.
# 这样才能够炸出细细的蛋丝
It's the only way to fry fine egg shreds.
# 第四
Fourth,
# 葱花必须分三次下入锅中
The scallions must be added to the wok in three batches.
# 最后一次下入葱花炒至断生即可出锅
Stir-fry the scallions for the last time until they half cook, and it's ready to serve.
# 下面开始成品展示
Let's have a look at the finished dish.